<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Getting Started on MareNostrum</title><link>https://erturk.me/series/getting-started/</link><description>Recent content in Getting Started on MareNostrum</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 17:47:00 +0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://erturk.me/series/getting-started/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Getting Started Developing Qt with VS Code Development Containers as Simple as Possible</title><link>https://erturk.me/blog/getting-started-qt-with-vs-code/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 17:47:00 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://erturk.me/blog/getting-started-qt-with-vs-code/</guid><description>Disclaimer — This is just my humble opinion and maybe there is more convenient way out there for this purpose.
For this purpose I already prepared a repo on GitHub1. The repo is a collection of some experimental works on AI, Image Processing, Qt Qml and embedded RPC. The procedure is is simple as follow.
Requirements Any Linux Distribution (tested on Debian 11) with Wayland Display Manager Docker daemon VS Code with Remote Container extension.</description></item><item><title>A Collection Related FEMM Magnetic</title><link>https://erturk.me/blog/a-collection-related-femm-magnetic/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 17:21:33 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://erturk.me/blog/a-collection-related-femm-magnetic/</guid><description>The collection of FEMM software examples and Libraries can be cloned from as follow.
1 $ git clone https://github.com/ierturk/femm-magnetic-collection.git FEMM Finite Element Analysis Software is available freely from here1
The Collection BLDC Machine Analysis Generating animated images from FEMM solutions Java FEMM Link and Java PowerLab integration Java FEMM Link for acces to FEMM from Java programs SciCos FEMM Link. The SciCos is the predecessor of SciLab/XCos.</description></item><item><title>How Did We Get Here?</title><link>https://erturk.me/blog/how-did-we-get-here/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 16:21:33 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://erturk.me/blog/how-did-we-get-here/</guid><description>Before we decided to use a static website generator, we tried a few other ones like Thumblr, Ghost. Here is my experince with Ghost. Various open source tools and software was used to build our previous Ghost Blog site as follow. Tools and Platforms Digital Ocean Debian 11 Droplet Docker Containers Ghost Node JS blogging framework MariaDB database server nginx proxy server Let&amp;rsquo;s Encrypt SSL Key provider GitHub Remark42 Comment System How to Run All of procedure is explained on the GitHub1 repo README.</description></item></channel></rss>